[{"id": "5febafc77e83c707845b2100", "question": "What is a sound bath?", "answer": "A meditation technique", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e9", "question": "How many calories do the US Postal Service stamps contain?", "answer": "One-tenth of a calorie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339188", "question": "In the TV show \"Futurama\", what was Uranus renamed to?", "answer": "Urectum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fe", "question": "Who played the role of Arnold on the ABC sitcom \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Pat Morita", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b8", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Pisces\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b492", "question": "Which country were the 1896 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4d", "question": "An Apgar score is given to what?", "answer": "Health of newborns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008cbecf842fa4c4ba96a1", "question": "What is a community of ants called?", "answer": "Colony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c625", "question": "How many stars does Aries consist of?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f94", "question": "Which science fiction writer developed a series of ethics for robots known as the \"Laws of Robotics\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01c", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"The Texas Chain Saw Massacre\"?", "answer": "John Larroquette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb09", "question": "Infantry, Cavalry, and Artillery cards are key to what Parker Brothers game?", "answer": "Risk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b30", "question": "How many sizes does the Grinch's heart grow on Christmas Day?", "answer": "Three", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592ead81f83302ff91e4647e", "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?", "answer": "A gold coin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a213", "question": "What cartoon, from the Talkertoon series, marked the first appearance of Betty Boop?", "answer": "Dizzy Dishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc2e56de0eb824d4052e7", "question": "Where is Blyde River Canyon, one of the largest canyons on Earth?", "answer": "South Africa -- At more than 16 miles long and 2,624 feet (26 km) deep, it is one of South Africa\u2019s most spectacular natural wonders.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c029", "question": "What sport is sometimes called rugger?", "answer": "Rugby union", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062d85c9d816e292245c33", "question": "Who painted \"Sunday Afternoon on the Island of La Grande Jatte\"?", "answer": "It is the painting of Neo-Impressionist Georges Seurat, whose techniques using tiny brushstrokes became known as Pointillism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e60", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Stewie Griffin?", "answer": "Seth MacFarlane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddd206d333868d34d709", "question": "Besides \"Axis Sally\", who was another famous propaganda broadcaster for the Nazis?", "answer": "Berlin Betty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b432", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising start?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f14afe83fe1f2a824c16", "question": "What ancient astrological event is December 25th also associated with?", "answer": "December 25 was the date of the winter solstice on the Roman calendar.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab1bb0baab681b0929219b", "question": "Which Canadian city is host to the Canadian International Autoshow?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9b43ebfabb9c85d8a983", "question": "What Norse explorer introduced Christianity to Greenland around 1000 A.D.?", "answer": "Leif Erikson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6c", "question": "What is the name of the sequel to the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Staying Alive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23d", "question": "What was Elton John's fourth studio album?", "answer": "Madman Across the Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25af1b63e5727cf5a4857", "question": "The song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\" was the title track to which film?", "answer": "Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc9", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b81", "question": "Who played Jill Taylor on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Patricia Richardson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f0", "question": "Who painted \"The Boy in the Red Vest\"?", "answer": "Paul C\u00e9zanne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b525", "question": "What is Wasabi?", "answer": "Japanese horseradish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b923", "question": "What car company was named for the founder of Detroit?", "answer": "Cadillac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd5a27e83c707845b2163", "question": "What tool does Andy use in shaping his chess pieces in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A rock blanket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b005", "question": "Pat Garrett shot and killed what legendary outlaw?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Jacqueline Susann", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a979", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Eduskunta?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cf0924f0f7a362efd54a", "question": "In the first Super Mario Bros. game, in which level is the first three-world secret exit?", "answer": "World 1-2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1e", "question": "In which decade was the Three Mile Island nuclear disaster?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aea", "question": "What classic 1933 horror film's last line is, \"It was beauty who killed the beast\"?", "answer": "King Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8f", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"The Door in the Floor\" based on?", "answer": "A Widow for One Year", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdabcbc0b8cce1e6fda705f", "question": "Which food can be called \"marrowfat\"?", "answer": "Processed peas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc3", "question": "In what year was David Bowie awarded the Grammy Lifetime Achievement Award?", "answer": "2006", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c764", "question": "What was the name of the IBM supercomputer which defeated chess champion Garry Kasparov in a 1997 match?", "answer": "Deep Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f7fa01dd7bf43be5e83b", "question": "Aichmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Needles or sharp objects", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d18", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Ciccone?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaefff83302ff91e4648f", "question": "The Pindus is the main mountain range in what country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d9", "question": "What organ in the human body is primarily affected by cystic fibrosis?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909ccb3bb53d1af658864e2", "question": "Which composer wrote the classical piece \"Messiah\"?", "answer": "George Frideric Handel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2a", "question": "Who wrote \"The Pisan Cantos\" while in prison?", "answer": "Ezra Pound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86c", "question": "In a game of Hearts, what term describes winning every heart and the queen of spades?", "answer": "Shooting the Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a41", "question": "What \"couple\" would be known as Fischbacher and Horn if they went by their last names?", "answer": "Siegfried & Roy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7a", "question": "How many pockets are there on a snooker table?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e482fe83fe1f2a824bb5", "question": "In the last six months of the war, what was the U.S. strategy for winning the conflict with Japan?", "answer": "Break the Japanese will with massive bombing raids on Japanese cities", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8c56ec223966ae8f8848", "question": "The 1994 \"Leon\" was the motion-picture debut of which one of its stars?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a746", "question": "Nevada is nicknamed the \"Silver State\" in honor of what?", "answer": "Silver mines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbaed8f0738315b1fb74e31", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a597", "question": "What do folks from Louisiana and Mississippi call sluggish creeks and marshy lakes?", "answer": "Bayous", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f5", "question": "What 2003 film was subtitled \"The Far Side of the World\"?", "answer": "Master and Commander", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bff", "question": "What movie does the line \"Nobody puts Baby in the corner\" hails form?", "answer": "Dirty Dancing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339013", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Northanger Abbey\"?", "answer": "Jane Austen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ee2406d333868d34d774", "question": "What lobster organ is made into a delicacy known as \"tomalley\"?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf2", "question": "Hydrosis is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Sweating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe52f931bf59ab7d2e38116", "question": "How many spikes are on the Statue of Liberty's crown?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c33f877e98cb97778993", "question": "Where is the world's first underwater hotel?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba62", "question": "What was the nickname of the 1960\u2019s model born Leslie Hornby?", "answer": "Twiggy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd1", "question": "Who became the 17th president, after Abraham Lincoln was assassinated?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c214877e98cb97778985", "question": "What is the smallest borough of New York City by land area?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64d", "question": "What animal lives in a lodge?", "answer": "The Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e5", "question": "Guitarist Brian May was part of what popular band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc948b60f0007efaba0e5e", "question": "What did Bob Ross specialize in doing?", "answer": "Painting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338969", "question": "Which 18-year-old married 26-year-old Anne Hathaway in November 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd8210cd0de9af39e9d46a2", "question": "What year did the War of 1812 end?", "answer": "1815", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8a", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Cockatrice?", "answer": "Rooster and serpent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99a", "question": "What was the original name of the John F. Kennedy International Airport in New York?", "answer": "Idlewild Airport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950b", "question": "Who plays the role of Martin Riggs in the Lethal Weapon movie series?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049c1ccf93664eb10486a4", "question": "In which North American city would you find Joe Shuster Way?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc29", "question": "What year was football player, David Beckham, born?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feba92b7e83c707845b20d2", "question": "Sailors from years past suffered from scurvy due to a lack of what?", "answer": "Vitamin C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c89efbde8045e48466de", "question": "What are names of the five layers of Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "The atmosphere has five different layers: the troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, and exosphere.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4de3306d333868d34d710", "question": "What name is given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cdd6bb53d1af658864ed", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a170", "question": "Which band had a hit in 1983 with the song \"True\"?", "answer": "Spandau Ballet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8e", "question": "In Botticelli's \"The Birth of Venus\", what is Venus standing on as she rides to shore?", "answer": "A seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d99", "question": "What author created the character of Uncle Tom?", "answer": "Harriet Beecher Stowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a553423e1c6f9840ba31a2", "question": "In ancient Rome what was the \"Tabularium\"?", "answer": "\"Hall of Public Records\", or the official records office", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25a6bb63e5727cf5a4853", "question": "Which rapper had hits including \"Who Am I (What's My Name)?\" and \"Gin And Juice\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff6", "question": "What is Johnny Chase's nickname on the TV show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Drama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339071", "question": "Stephen King's Dark Tower series is about a Gunslinger named what?", "answer": "Roland Deschain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"rodeo\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c947", "question": "Copper gets its name from which Mediterranean country?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59675fb62b59efe0e9417e9a", "question": "What Country music singer had a #1 single with \"You Look Like I Need A Drink\"?", "answer": "Justin Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b351", "question": "Which US President was the first to have an indoor Christmas tree in the White House?", "answer": "Benjamin Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fb", "question": "How many US state names begin with \"New\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c452", "question": "What are there 270 of in the average human baby but only 206 in an adult?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4a6dff048f679a45abc3", "question": "Mariner IV sent the first pictures of which planet back to Earth?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbc90ec60f0007efaba0e55", "question": "Dr. Jonathan Crane is the real name of which DC Comics supervillain?", "answer": "Scarecrow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d21", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Days of Thunder\"?", "answer": "Car racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e2fd06d333868d34d72b", "question": "Which conflict ended with the \"Good Friday Agreement\"?", "answer": "The Troubles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea481fff048f679a45abaf", "question": "Which medical term means vomiting?", "answer": "Emesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b10", "question": "Other than boxing, what does Maggie Fitzgerald do for a living in \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "She is a waitress", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a55820565ad31a57c7ca", "question": "What color were the first taxis in America?", "answer": "Red and green", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad52", "question": "What was the real first name of the First Lady known as Mamie Eisenhower?", "answer": "Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0af", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Beggars Banquet\"?", "answer": "Rolling Stones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb4", "question": "Each Pac-Man maze features 240 regular dots and how many larger \"power pellets\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cfc6877e98cb97778a54", "question": "What is Lynchburg, Tennessee famous for?", "answer": "Jack Daniels whiskey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071bc23745b36be73039c4", "question": "What is the only food that cannot give Tony Chu a psychic sensation in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "Beets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f83", "question": "What was Balki's home island on TV's \"Perfect Strangers\"?", "answer": "Mypos", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b7ca01dd7bf43be5e7e9", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c159", "question": "What is a Hurdy-Gurdy?", "answer": "Stringed instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51351ff04d658268c92d8", "question": "Social Darwinists believe that human societies progress through what?", "answer": "Competition, since the strong survive and the weak perish.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9816ebfabb9c85d8a969", "question": "In Formula One what does it mean when a black flag is being waved?", "answer": "Disqualification", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339235", "question": "Who played little Gertie in the movie \"E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339446", "question": "Which \"Friends\" star previously starred in a sitcom titled \"Top of the Heap\"?", "answer": "Matt LeBlanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcb", "question": "What's the ancient Greek word for \"great city\"?", "answer": "Megalopolis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ac", "question": "What is the singer Meat Loafs real name?", "answer": "Michael Lee Aday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4c", "question": "Who was the fifth president of the United States?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c3", "question": "What country covers an entire continent?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a018", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Anthony Hopkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338943", "question": "What is the name of cartoon character Charlie Brown's dog?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6b01dd7bf43be5e75a", "question": "What\u2019s another name for a footrest?", "answer": "Ottoman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d3", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Murray river?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c74", "question": "Rupert Giles was the librarian-mentor on what popular TV show?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d5", "question": "How many balls are normally racked in the triangle in pocket billiards?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339795", "question": "What was Mohammed Ali said to float like?", "answer": "A butterfly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e0", "question": "According to the first \"Austin Powers\" movie, what is Austin's middle name?", "answer": "Danger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b7af01dd7bf43be5e7e7", "question": "What is boxed macaroni and cheese called in Canada?", "answer": "Kraft Dinner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09f", "question": "At what theatre was Abraham Lincoln shot?", "answer": "Ford's Theatre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909d0acbb53d1af658864fd", "question": "What car did Frank buy for himself for Christmas in Season 6 of the TV show \"It\u2019s Always Sunny in Philadelphia\"?", "answer": "Lamborghini Countach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb8", "question": "What was Klaus Barbie\u2019s nickname?", "answer": "The Butcher of Lyon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f13", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Cate Blanchett and Judi Dench?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede6496ce05a3942286dfb", "question": "Who wrote the music for the Holiday classic film \"White Christmas\"?", "answer": "Irving Berlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ac", "question": "Which city was the setting for the TV show \"Room 222\"?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c88", "question": "What Oscar winner for Ed Wood turned down the role of Spock on Star Trek?", "answer": "Martin Landau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ba", "question": "Who famously said \"When in doubt tell the truth.\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc8", "question": "Who had a surprise cameo as \"Agent M\" in \"Men in Black II\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59dece53ea2747c8aff16d16", "question": "What is Joey's favourite food in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Sandwiches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a774", "question": "What African country completely surrounds the country of Lesotho?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada8", "question": "Who was the first Boy Scout to become a US president?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1f", "question": "Who was the first person to receive an artificial heart implant?", "answer": "Barney Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99b", "question": "By what more common name is the star cluster, Pleiades, better known as?", "answer": "Seven Sisters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592204f8a4edfd43a087ade7", "question": "Who was the top scorer at the 2014 FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "James Rodriguez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abda", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ed", "question": "What hurricane devastated Charleston, South Carolina in 1989?", "answer": "Hugo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b821e662d71a5365101d", "question": "What do \"Peter Pan\" author J.M. Barrie's initials stand for?", "answer": "James Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73e44eec85e375820b273", "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5eb", "question": "In which country is Angel Falls located?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b66a", "question": "Which Pac-Man ghost appears first on the arcade game's list?", "answer": "Shadow (Blinky)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe526241bf59ab7d2e380f5", "question": "What is the longest event at the Olympics?", "answer": "Race walk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d06d97870e6f05ba600859", "question": "Who directed the 1986 film \"The Fly\"?", "answer": "David Cronenberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a14", "question": "Where does Spanish rain fall, according to \"My Fair Lady\"?", "answer": "On the plain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b03de662d71a53650fc4", "question": "What feature marks the entrance to the Louvre?", "answer": "Glass pyramid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a728cdf6bcd28c11938328d", "question": "What was used for blood in Hitchcock's \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Chocolate syrup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad49", "question": "In 1978, what terrorist group kidnapped and murdered former Italian prime minister Aldo Moro?", "answer": "Red Brigade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339983", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's self-documentary?", "answer": "Puke-a-hontas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97d", "question": "What nuts are used to make a Satay sauce?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5fec5dad637d903c8828", "question": "Lei Day is a special May Day celebration held in which of America's states?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b748", "question": "What country invented the Winter Olympic sport of bobsleigh?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a384", "question": "What is the capital of Ontario?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601370831381754895396382", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", the fictitious film that Kevin watches, \"Angels with Filthy Souls\", is a homage to what real film?", "answer": "\"Angels with Dirty Faces\" -- It is a 1938 gangster film starring James Cagney and Pat O'Brien.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8c", "question": "Who was engaged to magician David Copperfield for six years in the 1990's?", "answer": "Claudia Schiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18c", "question": "What year did astronaut Neil Armstrong pass away?", "answer": "2012", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049ddecf93664eb10486b1", "question": "What year was the original film \"Friday the 13th\" released?", "answer": "1980", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be78", "question": "What is the shade of a Tiffany lamp made of?", "answer": "Stained glass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc39", "question": "What do the initials in O.J. Simpson's name stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec88caec223966ae8f8823", "question": "Which pop media icon was recently memorialized in \"World of Warcraft\" in late 2018?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d4", "question": "How many ounces of coffee are there in a Starbucks \"tall\" size?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94627ccba3ffe45786d3", "question": "What element has the atomic number 98?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be77", "question": "What does an NFL referee signal by stretching his arms out at his sides with his palms down?", "answer": "Unsportsmanlike Conduct", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e242fe83fe1f2a824b9d", "question": "On which region of the Soviet Union did Hitler place the highest priority?", "answer": "Ukraine and southern Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dc", "question": "Who played the role of Charles on \"Charles in Charge\"?", "answer": "Scott Baio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2a", "question": "In the US Army, what four ranks lie between First Lieutenant and Brigadier General?", "answer": "Captain, Major, Lieutenant Colonel and Colonel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887a", "question": "What was the first part of J.R.R. Tolkien's Lord of the Rings trilogy?", "answer": "The Fellowship of the Ring", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b2", "question": "Who played the male starring role in 1967 film \"The Graduate\"?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b4", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan is more famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e8c2fe83fe1f2a824bde", "question": "Which prominent Kurd, born in Tikrit, united Muslim forces against the crusaders in the 12th century?", "answer": "Saladin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80409de59ea584496fea2", "question": "Which popular children's novel did Dodie Smith publish in 1956?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbd", "question": "What model was married to musician Travis Barker?", "answer": "Shanna Moakler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3f16ce05a3942286ead", "question": "Which national monument does Cary Grant climb in \"North by Northwest\"?", "answer": "Mount Rushmore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c821877e98cb977789de", "question": "Where was shoe manufacturer Reebok founded?", "answer": "Bolton, England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b585", "question": "What is the Canadian dollar coin called?", "answer": "Loonie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede5626ce05a3942286deb", "question": "In \"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" who chose the tree for the school's Christmas Pageant?", "answer": "Charlie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339597", "question": "Musical duo Kaoma introduced the world to which dance in 1989?", "answer": "Lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388aa", "question": "What is the last name of brothers Dmitri, Ivan, Alyosha and Smerdyakov?", "answer": "Karamazov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b957", "question": "What golfer is nicknamed the \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339377", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1997 movie \"Titanic\" win?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c30ff04d658268c9315", "question": "In the 7th chapter of the Gospel of Luke, Jesus raises a young man from the dead in which village?", "answer": "Nain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73ddfeec85e375820b26e", "question": "Plymouth is the capital of what territory?", "answer": "Montserrat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b545", "question": "What does Canada mean in Iroquoian?", "answer": "Village", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc106e469bb8041d07a06e", "question": "What do you call a spiritual ceremony in which there is a deliberate attempt to contact the spirit of a deceased person?", "answer": "Seance", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b612", "question": "In baseball, which number references the shortstop?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3efeb8b5801b8f54a7fb8", "question": "Which software giant was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico in 1975?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca3", "question": "What name was given to people who made illegal booze during prohibition?", "answer": "Moonshiners", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f8", "question": "What animated TV show featured characters that repeatedly said \"Helllloooo Nurse!\"?", "answer": "Animaniacs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc85", "question": "What political figure is married to former \"In Living Color\" star Alexandra Wentworth?", "answer": "George Stephanopoulos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec25668dc25ca9e12ef63e", "question": "What Ray Bradbury novel is named for temperature at which paper catches fire?", "answer": "Fahrenheit 451", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ac", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59220535a4edfd43a087ade8", "question": "How high is the center of the tennis court net?", "answer": "3 feet, or 91 centimetres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968d", "question": "On the TV show \u201cFriends,\u201d what was the name of Ross\u2019 pet monkey?", "answer": "Marcel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6c", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Starbuck?", "answer": "Dale Robertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16973f7c52aae91cc07d1", "question": "In 1861, Julius Sturgis started the first US commercial bakery that made what?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5c", "question": "Oldest son Al was the first ringmaster of what famous circus?", "answer": "Ringling Brothers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e1", "question": "What do SETI programs search for?", "answer": "Extraterrestrial Intelligence", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded09aea2747c8aff16d2a", "question": "What is extracted from the ore cassiterite?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a177", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Kimono My House\"?", "answer": "Sparks\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3c8aff048f679a45ab40", "question": "Chromophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffce41cf6db9ac4808d05", "question": "What is the capital of Bavaria?", "answer": "Munich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28c", "question": "Who is Metallica's drummer?", "answer": "Lars Ulrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903f", "question": "Which movie star published an autobiography in 2002 entitled \"Lucky Man\"?", "answer": "Michael J. Fox", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339883", "question": "In Harry Potter, who is it that reveals to Harry that he is a wizard?", "answer": "Hagrid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4d", "question": "Natty Bumppo was the creation of which author?", "answer": "James Fenimore Cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a832", "question": "The city of Mumbai in India was formerly known by what name?", "answer": "Bombay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b182", "question": "What English captain was the first to visit the Galapagos Islands?", "answer": "Richard Hawkins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec88acec223966ae8f8821", "question": "LCS is the acronym for a professional eSports league centered around which game?", "answer": "League of Legends", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b086", "question": "What river did George Washington cross before the Battle of Trenton in the American Revolution?", "answer": "Delaware river", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a208", "question": "What is singer Wynonna Judd's real name?", "answer": "Christina Clair Ciminella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b748364247bf200fb870", "question": "What is the atomic number for Hydrogen?", "answer": "1", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe771bfeec85e375820b2fe", "question": "Where are sky burials still performed?", "answer": "Tibet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339529", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for her role as Lisa Rowe in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Angelina Jolie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a454", "question": "Doha is the capital of which Middle-Eastern country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a44020565ad31a57c7ba", "question": "The first U.S. transcontinental airmail service connected New York with which city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339378", "question": "Johann Van der Smut is better known as what?", "answer": "Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8c", "question": "How many total combined red and black numbers are there on a roulette wheel?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca85", "question": "What culinary ingredient is French scientist Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s credited with inventing?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada3", "question": "Who was better known as Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Robert Leroy Parker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f86", "question": "What is the fourth book in the Harry Potter series?", "answer": "The Goblet Of Fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e4", "question": "What type of wool can come from a rabbit?", "answer": "Angora", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb6", "question": "Who invented the spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ec7240f57c9fcac0ce7197d", "question": "What was the pennant number of HMS Hood?", "answer": "51", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c6", "question": "What hurricane devastated Charleston, South Carolina in 1989?", "answer": "Hugo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c9af0775fa611bce67ee", "question": "What\u2019s the main difference between a bay and bow window?", "answer": "Number of sections -- Bay windows usually have three sections while bow windows have anywhere from four to six.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e024fe83fe1f2a824b87", "question": "Who organized the famous \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Theodore Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b1746afbb2d29f81593b709", "question": "How many stories are there in Chaucer's \"The Canterbury Tales\"?", "answer": "24", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b3b5e662d71a53650fe2", "question": "Which famous composer produced his first operas at age 12?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a486", "question": "Mount Etna is located on which island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e801ccde59ea584496fe93", "question": "Where is the \"House of the Seven Gables\" located?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4bba49076251badbeac7", "question": "How many rooms are there in Buckingham Palace (total number)?", "answer": "775 -- It includes 19 State rooms, 92 offices, 52 Royal and guest bedrooms, 188 bedrooms for staff and 78 bathrooms.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e5", "question": "In Judaism, what day of the week is considered a day of rest?", "answer": "Saturday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f63301dd7bf43be5e830", "question": "What is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Ruby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d0", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was rich on Monday but broke on Sunday?", "answer": "Solomon Grundy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e3", "question": "At what age did Buffalo Bill become a rider for the Pony Express?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6f75a9e54d890926f6d1", "question": "What was the capital of Michigan before Lansing?", "answer": "Detroit -- Due to Detroit's proximity to Canada, a perceived threat at the time, Lansing became the state's capital in 1847.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6f18a9e54d890926f6ce", "question": "What color are gondolas required to be painted in Venice?", "answer": "Black -- A 17th century doge's decree dictated that all gondolas must be painted with six coats of black paint.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3bc9f4f032c0db195b475", "question": "On which island was Napoleon exiled in 1815?", "answer": "St. Helena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995c", "question": "Who were the two villains in the movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "The Penguin and Catwoman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339055", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, italy", "category": "arts"}]